[
    {
        "question": "When facing Mount Rushmore, which president`s head is farthest to your left?",
        "answer": "George Washington"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the two official languages of Guam?",
        "answer": "Chamorro and English"
    },
    {
        "question": "Chamorro is one of the official languages of which country?",
        "answer": "Guam"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the Australian state, Queensland?",
        "answer": "Brisbane"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation`s legislative body is named the Diet?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation`s legislative body is named The House of Lords?",
        "answer": "The United Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "U.S. state Florida was named for what?",
        "answer": "It`s flowers -- Spanish explorer Juan Ponce de Le\u00f3n named the area where he first landed Pascua Florida, or `Easter of Flowers.`"
    },
    {
        "question": "Luzon, Visayas, and Mindanao are island groups that belong to what country?",
        "answer": "The Philippines -- All 2,000 of the inhabited islands in the Philippines belong to one of the country`s three island groups."
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city is named after Saint Francis of Assisi?",
        "answer": "San Francisco"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Mediterranean island is said to be named after its inhabitants who were skilled in the use of slings?",
        "answer": "The Balearic Islands"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city features Asia`s largest spice market?",
        "answer": "Delhi, India"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are sky burials still performed?",
        "answer": "Tibet"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is New York`s state bird?",
        "answer": "Bluebird"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country hosts the world`s highest marathon?",
        "answer": "Nepal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state has a town named after a game show?",
        "answer": "New Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mountain is depicted in Toblerone chocolate bars` logo?",
        "answer": "The Matterhorn"
    },
    {
        "question": "What large red flower is the floral emblem of New South Wales?",
        "answer": "Waratah"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the most Northerly African country through which the Greenwich meridian passes?",
        "answer": "Algeria"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where does the famous `running of the bulls` take place?",
        "answer": "Pamplona"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which African country had its capital transferred to Abuja?",
        "answer": "Nigeria"
    },
    {
        "question": "`Upon the long river` is the English translation of the name of which US state?",
        "answer": "Connecticut"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country was the Rosetta Stone found?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Albert Canal links Liege with which city?",
        "answer": "Antwerp"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what sort of landscape would you find an erg?",
        "answer": "Desert"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major city lies on the River Torrens?",
        "answer": "Adelaide"
    },
    {
        "question": "What state capital city lies on the River Torrens?",
        "answer": "Adelaide"
    },
    {
        "question": "Adelaide is the capital of which Australian state?",
        "answer": "South Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the state of South Australia?",
        "answer": "Adelaide"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what U.S. state can you find a vending machine that dispenses full pecan pies?",
        "answer": "Texas -- Along Highway 71 in Cedar Creek, is the the family-owned Berdoll Pecan Farm vending machine."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the smallest South American country",
        "answer": "Suriname"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is the farthest from an ocean?",
        "answer": "Kyrgyzstan -- Of the 49 landlocked countries in the world, Kyrgyzstan is the farthest from an ocean at 1,620 miles."
    },
    {
        "question": "What point in the world is farthest from an ocean?",
        "answer": "Eurasian Pole of Inaccessibility (or `EPIA`) -- It is located in China`s Xinjiang region near the border with Kazakhstan."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the national flower of Scotland?",
        "answer": "Thisle -- There are a few legends as to how the purple-flowered plant captured the hearts of the Scots, but none have substance."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the national dish of Ukraine?",
        "answer": "Borscht"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river forms most of the border between the US states Georgia and Alabama?",
        "answer": "Chattahoochee river"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Haiti?",
        "answer": "Port-au-Prince"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city is Purdue University located?",
        "answer": "West Lafayette, IN"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only US state whose entire northern border is formed by a river?",
        "answer": "Kentucky"
    },
    {
        "question": "What European capital lies at the mouth of the Liffey River?",
        "answer": "Dublin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What animal does California have on its state flag?",
        "answer": "Bear"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Mekong river?",
        "answer": "Vietnam"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Colorado river?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Murray river?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Guam?",
        "answer": "Hagatna"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Middle Eastern country`s highest elevation point is Haji Ibrahim?",
        "answer": "Iraq"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is known as the `Hashemite Kingdom`?",
        "answer": "Jordan"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which capital city would you find the Marley Museum?",
        "answer": "Kingston"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Spanish-speaking nation got its name from its position on the Equator?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the highest mountain in Greece?",
        "answer": "Mount Olympus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What important crop is the Rhine Valley in Germany known for growing?",
        "answer": "Grapes"
    }
]